Guide to the Fred W. Voget Papers 1935-1996
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Crow Indian research, 1936-1995; Series II; 5.0 linear feet
  - Notes on modern Crow politics, interviews 1980 & 1987, other undated (Box-folder 9/19)
  - Notes on telephone interview with Frank Voget Lefthand regarding political changes, 1994-01-04 (Box-folder 9/20)
  - General notes, undated (Box-folder 9/21)
  - Notes generally titled "scattered data on sundance," some interviews, undated (Box-folder 9/22)
  - Interview notes from reminiscences of "Ball", 1939-08-08 - 1939-08-11 (Box-folder 9/23)
  - News clipping about Sun Dance news rights, 1987 (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Pencil drawing of Sun Dance staff, undated (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Typed notes on Sun Dance, participants and dates, undated (Box-folder 9/26)
  - Interview letter with response from Pete Lefthand on marriage, fasting, medicine doll, and Sun Dance, 1947-04-08 (Box-folder 9/27)
  - Notes on Crow, legendary events and history, undated (Box-folder 9/28)
  - Notes on Hidatsa, cultural background for Crow, undated (Box-folder 9/29)
  - Notes on Crow-Hidatsa Relations, undated (Box-folder 9/30)
  - Notes comparing Mountain Crow and River Crow, undated (Box-folder 9/31)
  - Notes on treaties, undated (Box-folder 9/32)
  - Notes on trade, undated (Box-folder 9/33)
  - Notes on pre-reservation, undated (Box-folder 9/34)
  - Notes on reservation life, interview, 1984, and other undated (Box-folder 9/35)
  - Note on agent regulation of Crow social style, undated (Box-folder 9/36)
  - Notes on inter-tribal relations and view of other tribes, undated (Box-folder 9/37)
  - Various appellations applied to the Crows, undated (Box-folder 9/38)
  - Notes on Joseph Medicine-Crow, interview, 1987-06-23, undated (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Notes on gestures and sign language, undated (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Notes from readings on character traits assigned to Crows, undated (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Notes on Crow perspective of territory, undated (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Notes on Crow clans, interview, 1988-09-01, undated (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Notes on father's clan, undated (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Notes on relationships between clans, undated (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Crow dance societies, interview, 1984, 1987, 1988 (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Notes on adoption, undated (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Notes on kinship behavior, undated (Box-folder 10/10)
  - Notes on kinship terminology, undated (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Notes on joking relationship, undated (Box-folder 10/12)
  - Notes on local divisions, bands, undated (Box-folder 10/13)
  - Notes on chiefs and political organization, undated (Box-folder 10/14)
  - Notes on camp layout and organization, undated (Box-folder 10/15)
  - Notes on camp circle, undated (Box-folder 10/16)
  - Notes on conflict resolution, undated (Box-folder 10/17)
  - Notes on police camp, undated (Box-folder 10/18)
  - Notes on teepees, undated (Box-folder 10/19)
  - Notes on annual calendar months, undated (Box-folder 10/20)
  - Notes on ethnobotany, undated (Box-folder 10/21)
  - Notes on food collection (women), undated (Box-folder 10/22)
  - Notes on hunting, undated (Box-folder 10/23)
  - Notes on transportation, undated (Box-folder 10/24)
  - Notes on horses, undated (Box-folder 10/25)
  - Notes on horse equipment, saddle, undated (Box-folder 10/26)
  - Notes on dogs, undated (Box-folder 10/27)
  - Notes on food, undated (Box-folder 10/28)
  - Notes on maternal culture and technology, undated (Box-folder 10/29)
  - Notes on kitchen and eating, undated (Box-folder 10/30)
  - Notes on bow and arrow, undated (Box-folder 10/31)
  - Notes on food preparation, undated (Box-folder 10/32)
  - Notes on eating and etiquette, undated (Box-folder 10/33)
  - Notes on drinking and smoking, undated (Box-folder 10/34)
  - Notes on tanning and hides, undated (Box-folder 10/35)
  - Notes on bags or containers, undated (Box-folder 10/36)
  - Notes on admired types and behavior, undated (Box-folder 10/37)
  - Notes on body customs and care, undated (Box-folder 10/38)
  - Notes on hair, undated (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Notes on cleanliness, undated (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Notes on dress, undated (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Notes on age categories and biological maturation, interviews, 1939, undated (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Notes on burial, undated (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Notes on mourning, undated (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Notes on dances, reading and interview, undated (Box-folder 11/7)
  - Notes on modern dance, undated (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Interview notes regarding ghost signals and death, 1988 (Box-folder 11/9)
  - Interview notes regarding medicine necklaces and names for babies, 1987-01-18 (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Note on Glad Song, interview, 1988-10-17 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - Notes on praise songs, interview, 1988-10-17, undated (Box-folder 11/12)
  - Notes on Crow Indian Fair, interview, 1988-10-17, undated (Box-folder 11/13)
  - Notes on games - competition, undated (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Notes on gambling, undated (Box-folder 11/15)
  - Notes on home life, undated (Box-folder 11/16)
  - Notes on sleeping arrangements, undated (Box-folder 11/17)
  - Note on acculturation - change, undated (Box-folder 11/18)
  - Notes on acculturation, undated (Box-folder 11/19)
  - List of early schools for Native Americans and other note on education, undated (Box-folder 11/20)
  - Notes from readings on coyote, undated (Box-folder 11/21)
  - Interviews on "Old Man Coyote", undated (Box-folder 11/22)
  - Interview with F. Lefthand on the sun, woodpecker, and Washington's Birthday, undated (Box-folder 11/23)
  - Interviews with Marshall Lefthand on prayer, mystical power, and blessing, 1989 (Box-folder 11/24)
  - Interview with Marshall Lefthand regarding sexual abuse conference, 1989 (Box-folder 11/25)
  - Interview with Laverne Williamson, 4th of Pow Wow, 1989-06-29 (Box-folder 11/26)
  - Interview with F. Lefthand on descent of Crow from sun, 1989-07-16 (Box-folder 11/27)
  - Notes from telephone conversation with Barbara Lefthand, mention of fashion, 1990 (Box-folder 11/28)
  - Various interview notes with Frank Voget Lefthand on Tobacco Dance, Sun Dance, and Custer re-enactment, 1984, 1991-04-07 (Box-folder 11/29)
  - Notes on conversation with Ferole Pease, 1996-02-08 (Box-folder 11/30)
  - Interview notes on "stylish tendencies of Crow", 1996-02-08 (Box-folder 11/31)
  - Crow "notes to be transcribed to index cards", undated (Box-folder 11/32)
  - Letter from Ferole & Bill, 1987 (Box-folder 11/33)
  - Notes from interview with Frederick, May, 1993 (Box-folder 11/34)
  - Letter from T. Larson Medicine Horse, undated (Box-folder 11/35)
  - Interview with Feral Mae (Hogan) Pease, Crow Agency, Montana, undated (Box-folder 11/36)
  - Notes regarding Crow-Cheyenne conflict over Crow Agency Hospital, undated (Box-folder 11/37)
  - Interview with Bill Russell, Lodge Grass and Pryor, Montana, 1956, undated (Box-folder 11/38)
  - Interview with Bill Pease regarding Bill Russell, undated (Box-folder 11/39)
  - Note about Ben Jefferson, Lodge Grass, Montana, undated (Box-folder 11/40)
  - Interviews, notes, and records from Flathead Reservation, Montana, 1950, 1956, undated (Box-folder 11/41)
  - Interview with Sam and Flora Hathaway, Pryor, Montana, 1956-06-13 (Box-folder 11/42)
  - Interview with Poesy Edward Whiteman, Pryor, Montana, 1956 (Box-folder 11/43)
  - Interview with Mrs. E.A.K. Cashen, Pryor, Montana, undated (Box-folder 11/44)
  - Interview with Oliver Verme, Crow Agency, Montana, 1956 (Box-folder 11/45)
  - Interview with Josephine Russell, Lodge Grass, Montana 1956 (Box-folder 11/46)
  - Copy of Kronmiller letter discussing Crow Tribe Resolutions, 1956-06-06 (Box-folder 11/47)
  - One page unsigned resolution to alter Crow land lease terms, undated (Box-folder 11/48)
  - Copy of "Constitution and By-Laws of the Crow Tribal Council", undated (Box-folder 11/49)
  - Photocopies and notes from folder labeled "Mike Cowdrey", undated (Box-folder 11/50)
  - Kay Voget Crow notes, 1968-06-08 (Box-folder 11/51)
  - Letter from Agnes Deernose and Ataloa Hogan Harris, undated (Box-folder 11/52)
  - Handwritten list of literature supplied by D. Deernose, undated (Box-folder 11/53)
  - Crow giveaway feast given by George Goes-Ahead-Pretty of Pryor, 1946-04-28 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Arrow throwing interview, Crow, 1946-04-26 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Jack Covers-Up interview on sun dance, Crow, 1946-04-25 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Jim Blaine interview on sun dance, Crow, 1946-04-24 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Medicine Crow interview on sun dance, 1946-04-23 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Interview with Plays on sun dance, Crow, 1946-04-22 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Interviews on sun dance, Crow, 1946 and undated (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Interviews on sun dance, much shorthand, Crow, 1940s (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Notes for non-sun dance member questionnaire, undated (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Guide for sun dance member questionnaire, undated (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Sun dance interviews with Lynn St. Clair, Tom Wesaw, Tom Compton, and John Truhujo, Shoshoni, August 1948 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Interview with Antonius La Jennesse, Shoshoni, August 1948 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Interviews with Mrs. Mike T. Montour, Caughnawaga Iroquois, 1949, 1950 (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Signature of Pablo Juan Truhujo, undated (Box-folder 12/14)
  - List of Crow Agency sun dancers, 1944 (Box-folder 12/15)
  - Compiled lists and tables of sun dance and related data, undated (Box-folder 12/16)
  - Compiled lists of church membership status, undated (Box-folder 12/17)
  - Political questionnaire, undated (Box-folder 12/18)
  - Interviews with members and other information on Shoshoni-Arapahoe Council, 1948 (Box-folder 12/19)
  - Shoshoni-Arapahoe Joint Council Meetings, 1947, 1948 (Box-folder 12/20)
  - Meetings of the Business Councils of the Arapahoe and Shoshoni, 1940-12-06, 1941-12-11 (Box-folder 12/21)
- Field research notebooks, 1949-1993; Series III; 1.0 linear feet
  This series includes Voget's handwritten field research notebooks on the Shoshoni, the Iroquois, the Blackfeet, and the Crow. Many parts of the notebooks are written in shorthand. The Iroquois and Blackfeet notebooks were transcribed in 2003 and 2004.
  The series is arranged in chronological order.
  - Field research notebook, Shoshoni, some shorthand, 1948 (Box-folder 12/22)
  - Field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada, much shorthand, 1949-08-16, undated (Box-folder 12/23)
  - Transcription of field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada, much shorthand, 1949-08-16, undated (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Transcription of field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada (Box-folder 28/2)
  - Field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada, much shorthand, 1949 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Transcription of field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada, much shorthand, 1950 (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Transcription of field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada, much shorthand, 1950 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Transcription of field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada, some shorthand, 1950 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Transcription of field research notebook, Iroquois at Caughnawauga, Ontario, Canada (Box-folder 28/6)
  - Field research notebook, Blackfeet, mostly shorthand, 1956 (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Transcription of field research notebook, Blackfeet (Box-folder 28/7)
  - Field interview notebook, Crow, 1939-07-08 - 1939-07-20 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Field interview notebook, Crow, 1939-08-12 - 1939-08-17 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Field research notebook, Crow, no shorthand, 1986 (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Field research notebook, Crow, no shorthand, 1987 (Box-folder 13/10)
  - Field research notebook supplement, Crow, no shorthand, 1987 (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Field research notebook, Crow, 1993 (Box-folder 14/2)
- Crow language research, undated; Series IV; 1.0 linear feet
  This series includes a small amount of language research notes from secondary sources, but the bulk of the series consists of handwritten and typed cards with a word or phrase in English and the corresponding Crow word or phrase with pronunciation markings.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the English word or the significant word in a phrase.
  - Crow language research notes, undated (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Language cards with multiple words and phrases, undated (Box-folder 14/4)
  - "A", undated (Box-folder 14/5)
  - "B", undated (Box-folder 14/6)
  - "C", undated (Box-folder 14/7)
  - "D", undated (Box-folder 14/8)
  - "E", undated (Box-folder 14/9)
  - "F", undated (Box-folder 14/10)
  - "G", undated (Box-folder 15/1)
  - "H", undated (Box-folder 15/2)
  - "I", undated (Box-folder 15/3)
  - "J", undated (Box-folder 15/4)
  - "K", undated (Box-folder 15/5)
  - "L", undated (Box-folder 15/6)
  - "M", undated (Box-folder 15/7)
  - "N", undated (Box-folder 15/8)
  - "O", undated (Box-folder 15/9)
  - "P", undated (Box-folder 15/10)
  - "Q", undated (Box-folder 15/11)
  - "R", undated (Box-folder 15/12)
  - "S", undated (Box-folder 16/1)
  - "T", undated (Box-folder 16/2)
  - "T", undated (Box-folder 16/3)
  - "U", undated (Box-folder 16/4)
  - "W", undated (Box-folder 16/5)
  - "Y", undated (Box-folder 16/6)
- Writings, 1935-1996; Series V; 2.3 linear feet
  This series includes some of Voget's undergraduate papers, working drafts of articles and book chapters, and copies of published articles. The drafts preceded published works and probably a planned history of the Crow Indians that was not published at the time of processing.
  This series is arranged in rough chronological order within the categories of term papers, drafts, and published works.
  - Three copies of term paper for History of Social Thought class, 1935 (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Copy of term paper for History of Social Thought class, 1935 (Box-folder 16/8)
  - Paper for Main Currents of European Thought class, 1936 (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Analysis of social theorists for Contemporary Social Theories class, 1937 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Notes for lecture or article on perspective and focus in anthropology, undated (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Dissertation, The Diffusion of the Wind River Shoshone Sundance to the Crow Indians of Montana, 1948 (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Broad Crow article outline, undated (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Drafts of article or chapter on Crow Arrow Throw, 1946 (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Retyped or revised draft of "Social Life of the Crow Arrow Throwing Game", undated (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Draft of article, "William Big Day: A Crow Innovator", 1946 (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Draft of article "Anthropological Theory and Iroquois Ethnology, undated (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Draft of article or lecture entitled "The Status of American Indian Women: A Comparison of Crow and Iroquois Women", undated (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Draft of Voget introduction to later printing of Blankets and Moccasins, originally published in 1933, undated (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Notes for lecture or article on Crow Indians and Sun Dance, undated (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Draft of table of contents, notes, and bibliography for The Shoshoni-Crow Sun Dance, undated (Box-folder 17/12)
  - Early chapter outline for The Shoshoni-Crow Sun Dance, undated (Box-folder 17/13)
  - Notes and partial draft of Chapter 6 of The Shoshoni-Crow Sun Dance, undated (Box-folder 17/14)
  - Some chapter drafts for The Shoshoni-Crow Sun Dance, undated (Box-folder 17/15)
  - Index for The Shoshoni-Crow Sun Dance, A-N, undated (Box-folder 17/16)
  - Index for The Shoshon-Crow Sun Dance, O-Z, undated (Box-folder 17/17)
  - Organizing notes for They Call Me Agnes, undated (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Handwritten article or chapter, "Crow Mythology and the Creator", undated (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Letter from Enciclopedia Italiana, 1986 (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Draft of "Anthropology and Ethnology" for Enciclopedia Italiana, 1988 (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Article on Crow for publication in Handbook of North American Indians, Vol. 13, 1987 (Box-folder 18/5)
  - Notebook, possible organizing notes for manuscript, undated (Box-folder 18/6)
  - Drafts of chapters on Crow origins for history of Crow manuscript, 1991 (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Draft of chapters of Crow worldview for history of Crow manuscript, undated (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Drafts of chapter on Crow religion for manuscript on history of Crow, undated (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Drafts of chapter, "Religion in Crow Indian Culture and Culture History", 1989, 1990, 1994, undated (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Rough draft of chapter, "Crow Culture History", undated (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Draft of chapter, "Crow Origins", 1991 and undated (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Draft of chapter, "Sacred Design of Hidatsa Society and Culture", 1991 and undated (Box-folder 19/3)
  - "Work copies" of chapter, "Crow Culture", undated (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Draft of chapter, "Historic Crow Culture", undated (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Draft of chapter, "Reservation Culture", undated (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Drafts and correspondence in regard to Voget's introduction to reprint of Old Man Coyote by Frank Bird Linderman, 1995 (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Abstract, "Were the Crow Indians Conservationists?", undated (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Article or chapter on Arapahoe culture, undated (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Bibliography for unnamed manuscript, undated (Box-folder 19/10)
  - One page note on paper about Crow ceremonial rights, undated (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Bibliography of published articles by Voget, undated (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Article titled "The Folk Society - An Anthropological Application", 1954 (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Article titled "Forgotten Forerunners of Anthropology", undated (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Article titled "Anthropology and Sociology", undated (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Article titled "Man and Culture: An Essay in Changing Anthropological Interpretations", 1960 (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Article titled "American Indian Reformations and Acculturation", 1960 (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Article titled "Reform und Akkomadation: Unter Amerikanischen Indianern", undated (Box-folder 20/7)
  - Article titled "Comment on Robert K. Thomas' "The Redbird Smith Movement", 1961 (Box-folder 20/8)
  - Article, "Progress, Science, History, and Evolution in 18th and 19th Century Anthropology", 1967 (Box-folder 20/9)
  - Article titled "Anthropology in the Age of Enlightenment: Progress and Utopian Functionalism", 1968 (Box-folder 20/10)
  - Article titled, "A Six Nations' Diary, 1891-1894", 1969 (Box-folder 20/11)
  - Article titled, "The History of Cultural Anthropology", 1974 (Box-folder 20/12)
  - Article titled "Reflections on Acculturation Processes and Stages: A Reply to Deward E. Walker, Jr.", 1976 (Box-folder 20/13)
  - Academic Encyclopedia articles, undated (Box-folder 20/14)
  - Entry on Franz Boas in Dictionary of Scientific Biography, undated (Box-folder 20/15)
  - Article titled "Cultural Change and the American Indian", undated (Box-folder 20/16)
  - Article titled "Sacred Numerology and Management of the Universe by the Crow Indians", undated (Box-folder 20/17)
  - Article titled "Warfare and the Integration of Crow Indian Culture", undated (Box-folder 20/18)
  - Article titled "The Reservation Community as an Interactional System", undated (Box-folder 20/19)
  - Review titled "Ethnoscience Versus the Survey: Steps for Gathering Data", 1980 (Box-folder 20/20)
  - Article titled "The Crow Indian Give-Away", 1987 (Box-folder 20/21)
  - Article titled "Religion in Crow Indian Culture and Culture History", 1996 (Box-folder 20/22)
  - "Before the Indian Claims Commission: Docket Nos. 106 and 107: Osage Research Report," (missing title page, page 1, and bibliographic reference pages 357-371), 1946, 1966 (Box-folder 20/23)
- Photos, 1939-1989; Series VI; 2.5 linear feet
  This series includes Voget's photos, slides, and some negatives taken throughout his research. The bulk of the photos chronicle Crow activities such as the sun dance and arrow throw, feasts, and giveaways. A smaller number of photos are of specific individuals significant to Crow history and/or Voget's research. Another small group of photos pertain to Native American artifacts, the Shoshoni sun dance, and to Mohawk and other Six Nations groups. Most of the photos are very usable with the exception of photos 25/75 through 25/89, which are out of focus. Original photo captions and photo groupings were maintained where they existed. Otherwise, the photos in this series are arranged in rough thematic and chronological order. The slides are grouped at the end of this series.
  In 2012, additional or corrected information for some photographs and context about places and events was provided by Aaron Brien, a member of the Apsaalooke Nation, in consultation with other members of the Nation. This information was added with the preface [From Aaron Brien]. When a date was corrected, the correct date was placed in the date field.
  Digital copies of the materials in Box 20/Folder 30 through Box 26 are available online at https://umt.box.com/v/Mss318FredWVogetPapers. These digital copies were created in 2009 and are meant for reference only.
  - Photocopies of Crow photos from various publications, undated (Box-folder 20/24)
  - Negatives of pictures and maps from various publications, undated (Box-folder 20/25)
  - Color copies and photocopies of photos used in They Call Me Agnes, undated (Box-folder 20/26)
  - Negative strips relevant to They Call Me Agnes, circa 1980s (Box-folder 20/27)
  - Negative strips from photos used in They Call Me Agnes, circa 1980s (Box-folder 20/28)
  - Negative strips relevant to They Call Me Agnes, undated (Box-folder 20/29)
  - Joy, daughter of Robert Yellowtail and Agnes, undated (Box-folder 20/30, Photo number 318(VI):001)
  - Danny and dance troupe, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Standing: Tom Yellow Tail, Reginald Laubin. Sitting: Joseph Medicine Crow, Donnie Deernose, Henry Old Coyote. (Box-folder 20/31, Photo number 318(VI):002)
  - Agnes used in They Call Me Agnes, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Agnes Yellow Tail Deer Nose. (Box-folder 20/32, Photo number 318(VI):003)
  - Yellowtail family, circa 1930; [From Aaron Brien] Left to Right: Tom Yellow Tail, Carson Yellow Tail, Robert Yellow Tail, Lizzie (mother), Amy, and Agnes Yellow Tail. (Box-folder 20/33, Photo number 318(VI):004)
  - Agnes's father, Hawk with Yellow Tail, undated (Box-folder 20/34, Photo number 318(VI):005)
  - Amy, Agnes's sister, undated (Box-folder 20/35, Photo number 318(VI):006)
  - circa 1920 (Box-folder 20/36, Photo number 318(VI):007)
  - Agnes's mother at age 100, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Lizzie Yellow Tail at age 100, mother to Agnes Yellow Tail Deer Nose. (Box-folder 20/37, Photo number 318(VI):008)
  - Two rows of Crow women in traditional dress, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Amy Yellowtail the sister to Agnes Yellowtail Deernose. Amy was married to John White Man. (Box-folder 20/38, Photo number 318(VI):009)
  - Crow boarding school, Crow Agency, Montana, 1894 (Box-folder 20/39, Photo number 318(VI):010)
  - Crow Shoshoni Sun Dance, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] This sundance photo is of the first sundance held among the Apsaalooke people since 1875. (Box-folder 20/40, Photo number 318(VI):011)
  - Tripod reminder of Sun Dance, Pryor, Montana, June, 1941 (Box-folder 20/41, Photo number 318(VI):012)
  - John Truhujo praying for dancers to give them strength, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 20/42, Photo number 318(VI):013)